yieldkit.com 2019-05-05

# YieldKit - Performance Marketing Aggregator for Publishers

## Privacy Statement

Our data privacy statement, sets out how we handle personal data. We are aware of the importance to users of how personal data are handled and we assure you that we observe all relevant legal requirements. We consider the protection of your privacy to be of paramount importance. For this reason, compliance with the legal requirements on data privacy is, for us, a matter of course.

##### Group-Oriented Data Privacy

To which extent and in which form we process and save personal data depends on the concerned group of persons. Thereby we distinguish as follows: publisher, advertiser/merchant and user.

_Publishers_ are website operators, who use YieldKit services by implementing the YieldKit code to activate and integrate a JavaScript into their website. The management and use of the YieldKit account takes place over a web-based portal which is accessible through a browser-login.

_Advertisers/merchants_ are advertisers who use the YieldKit technologies to connect with publishers who use YieldKit services. Upon request, the management and use of a YieldKit account can take place over a web-based portal which is accessible through a browser-login.

We define _partners_ as both groups, advertisers/merchants and publishers.

_Users_ are website visitors, who use YieldKit’s publisher websites.

#### Who is YieldKit and what does the company offer

YieldKit is the leading Performance Marketing Aggregator in the German market. Based in Hamburg, the company connects publishers and advertisers in a unique way.

YieldKit technology enables publishers to connect their websites with intelligent monetization solutions. With just one integration publishers can automatically monetize their content and collect e-commerce behavioural data to optimize and aggregate new revenue streams for their business. YieldKit is the perfect solution for publishers and advertisers. Publishers are able to increase their revenue by connecting with more than 45.000 advertisers worldwide, while merchants increase their sales with high quality traffic, provided by YieldKit contextual solutions.

From the user perspective and under terms of data privacy the following YieldKit technology elements are relevant:

  1. Tracking of ad displays and clicks on advertising media, tracking of sales transactions
  2. Aggregated reporting (user-segmentation) in respect to e-commerce and behavioural data of the user. No personally identifiable information is given, just an aggregated and segmented report.

In this context no personal data, like names or e-mail addresses, identifiable to a natural person is ever visible. Which user data is visible and stored is defined in the section “Processed data, data sources and purpose of use, user data”.

#### Contact

YieldKit GmbH  
Oliver Krohne, CEO  
Jarrestraße 44b, 22303 Hamburg, Germany

Email: [info@yieldkit.com](mailto:info@yieldkit.com)  
Phone: [+49 40 416 204 01](tel:+49-40-416-204-01)

#### Data Protection Officer

Our contracted data protection officer is

ePrivacy GmbH  
represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer  
Große Bleichen 21, 20354 Hamburg

If you have any questions or concerns regarding data security, please contact us or our data protection officer at [privacy@yieldkit.com](mailto:privacy@yieldkit.com)

In case of any sensitive concerns please contact our data protection officer by mail, since e-mail communications carries more security risks.

#### Definition Personal Data

Personal data refers to any information about personal or factual circumstances of an identified or identifiable person. This includes information and details such as your name, home address or telephone number and also your e-mail address. This also includes indirect personal data like browser-version, location or used device, as long as this data is supplemented by an online-identifier.

#### Legal Basis

Your data are handled according to the following legal provisions:

  * With regard to data communicated for the newsletter, etc. with your consent, Art. 6(1) lit. (a) GDPR
  * With regard to services you use for the performance of a contract or in contractional initiation, Art. 6(1) lit. (b) GDPR
  * Otherwise, with particular regard to statistical data and online identifiers based on legitimate interests, Art 6(1) lit. (f) GDPR (see below)

#### Legitimate Interests

When handling your data, we pursue the following legitimate interests:

  * Improving our service
  * Protecting against misuse
  * Statistics

#### Processed Data, Data Sources and Purpose of Use

##### Which data in which way from whom and for which purpose will be saved

Personal data will only be collected by us to the extent and for the purpose for which you provide the data to us, e.g. for registration or during usage of a website which contains YielKit-Services.

##### Publishers

YieldKit saves the following registration data for contract fulfilment and customer care:

  1. First and last name
  2. Address (Street, house number, ZIP-code, city, state, country)
  3. Website(s)
  4. Email address(es)
  5. Login data
  6. Bank details/paypal
  7. Tax information
  8. User data (see user data)

The customer profiles are used for customer care. This includes: usage information of our services, technical and management-related updates, support, core data updates, provision of invoices or credit notes by email, archiving of tax related documents, provision of performance reports and analytics.

In some cases, to provide our services and to meet our contractual obligations, we must forward information about payment and/or contact information to advertisers or their representative organisation, if the publisher has commissioned YieldKit for respective services.

##### Advertisers/Merchants

YieldKit saves the following registration data for contract fulfilment and partner service:

  1. First and last name
  2. Address (Street, house number, ZIP-code, city, state, country)
  3. Website(s)
  4. Email address(es)
  5. Login data (if applicable)
  6. Tax information

The profiles are used for partner service. This includes: usage information of our services, technical and management-related updates, support, core data updates.

##### User Data

Furthermore, YieldKit collects data from users who visit a website which contains the YieldKit code and uses our services.

This contains only pseudonymised data, which does not include personal data and is not identifiable to a natural person. Nevertheless, it is possible to identify a characterizable profile. This data is collected by using a cookie.

Saved data is defined as follows:

  1. Behavioural data (which link is clicked)
  2. Browser and browser version
  3. Operating system
  4. Screen size
  5. Used device
  6. Country
  7. City
  8. Time of access
  9. Referrer (from which domain the user is accessing the website)
  10. Used online-shop and if applicable order value
  11. Anonymized IP-address (shortened)

The above defined data is supplemented by a random online-identifier (cookie-ID). Because of that it is a characterizable profile.

Personal data like names, addresses, email-addresses etc. are neither visible nor storable to YieldKit at any time.

The collected data is used for the following purposes:

  * Providing YieldKit services to partners
  * Solely aggregated reporting for partners (no detailed data is transferred)

Users who do not agree with the collection of their data can opt-out here.

##### _Notice for Publishers_

As a publisher based in the EU or handling data from EU-citizens you are obliged to comply with the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). For further information please visit:  
<https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>  
<http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679>

One part of the new requirements is to create transparency and to offer an opt-out; because of that you have to declare service providers like YieldKit on your website. Therefore, we highly recommend including a notice about YieldKit in your privacy policy. A text template follows:

_This website uses affiliate marketing links. If you click on these links and this results in a purchase, we receive commissions on this sale. For more information visit the website of our partner YieldKit. YieldKit tracks these sales, but never collects any personal data like your name or address. For more information about what kinds of data YieldKit collects and an opportunity to opt-out please visit the website<https://yieldkit.com/legal-notes/privacy-policy/>._

#### Retention Period

We retain your data,

  * if you have consented to this as part of processing, until such time as you withdraw your consent,
  * if we need the data to undertake an agreement, until such time as the contractual relationship with you ceases or legal retention periods expire,
  * if we use the data on the basis of a legitimate interest, until such time as your overriding interest obliges us to delete or anonymize them.

#### Data Protection

We have taken extensive technical and organizational measures to secure your data against potential risks, such as unauthorised login or access, unauthorised perusal, amendment or distribution, as well as against loss, deletion or misuse.

In order to protect your personal data against unauthorised access by third parties when being transmitted, we secure data transmissions, if necessary, using SSL encryption. This is a standard encryption procedure for online services, particularly for the Internet.

YieldKit saves and processes personal data, especially sensitive data like login-data or bank details, primarily in the EU. Should the processing or storage take place outside of the EU, YieldKit assures that the provider complies with the GDPR requirements and certifies this in a GDPR accepted manner.

#### Logfiles

Every time you access our web pages or pages using YieldKit services, usage data are transferred through your specific web browser and stored in the form of protocol files (known as server log files). The datasets stored in this way contain the following data:

  * The domain from which the user is accessing the website
  * Date and time of access
  * IP address of the accessing computer
  * Website(s) which the user is visiting in the context of the offering
  * Amount of data transferred; browser type and version
  * Operating system used; name of internet service provider
  * Indication of whether access was successful

These logfile datasets are analysed in anonymised form, to improve the offering and make it more user-friendly, to identify and resolve errors, and to control server workloads.

#### Definition Cookies

Cookies are small files that your browser stores on your PC in a directory designated specifically for this purpose. These cookies can be used e.g. to find out whether you have already visited a website. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. Nevertheless, you can change the settings in your browser, so that no cookies can be stored or so that your explicit agreement is required before any cookies are stored. You can also delete previously set cookies at any time. Please note that disabling cookies may result in your use of our website and YieldKit services being restricted.

##### Used Cookies

##### Session-Cookies

YieldKit uses session-cookies which support the website as well as the usage of partner accounts. After the end of the session or after a certain period of inactivity, the session cookies will expire automatically.

##### Additional Cookies

YieldKit also uses long-term cookies which automatically expire after 13 months. The purpose of these cookies is to collect usage data of our publisher’s websites. Furthermore, this information is used to optimize the services. The stored data does not contain any personal data like names or full IP-addresses. For details see “processed data, data sources and purpose of use, user data”.

##### Deactivation of Cookies

You can define individual cookie settings (cookie-type, consent and deletion) in your browser settings. Furthermore, there are other opt-out options whereby an opt-out-cookie is saved. As soon as cookies are deleted you must opt-out again.

#### Web Analysis

Like almost all website operators, we use analytical tools in the form of tracking software to ascertain the number of users using our website and how frequently they visit.

To enable us to optimize our website and our service, we use Google Analytics, which is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses what are known as “cookies”: these are text files stored on your computer and used to analyse your website usage. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be sent to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, within member states of the European Union, or in other states that are party to the agreement on the European Economic Area Google first abbreviates your IP address. The full IP address will only be transmitted in exceptional circumstances to one of Google's servers in the USA, where it will then be abbreviated. Google will use this information on behalf of our website operator to analyse your use of the website in order to compile reports about website activities for the website operator and to perform other services connected with the use of the website and of the Internet. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged or combined with other data by Google. You can prevent cookies from being stored by applying the appropriate settings in your browser software; please note, however, that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their full extent.

You may also prevent Google from collecting data generated by the cookie referring to your website usage (including your IP address), and from processing these data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de) . As an alternative to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices, please click on this link to prevent Google Analytics from collecting data in this website in future (the opt-out only works in this browser, and only for this domain). This stores an opt-out cookie on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you need to click on this link again. Further information is available at [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de) or at [www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html](https://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html) (general information on Google Analytics and data protection).

Please note that on this website, Google Analytics has been extended by the code “gat._anonymizeIp();”, to ensure anonymised collection of IP addresses (known as IP masking).

#### Third-Party Services

YieldKit reserves the right to transfer pseudonymized user data to the following third-party services. Only pseudonymized data is transferred. Personal data like names, email-addresses are neither visible nor transferable for YieldKit at any time. Affected user data is defined in the section “processed data, data sources and purpose of use, user data”.

The following service provider complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Further information and opt-out options are available using the links below the company.

Eyeota Pte Ltd  
12A Upper Circular Road  
058410 Singapore  
<http://www.eyeota.com/privacy-policy/#full-privacy-policy>

##### Further Third-Party Services (mainly relevant for YieldKit-Partners)

Pipedrive: Customer Relations Management System  
<https://www.pipedrive.com/en/privacy>

Mailchimp: Newsletter-Tool  
<https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

Autopilot: Customer Journey Software  
<https://www.autopilothq.com/legal/privacy-policy>

Happyfox: Ticket-System (Support)  
<https://www.happyfox.com/privacy-policy/>

Google: email accounts  
<https://policies.google.com/privacy>

Amazon Web Services: storage mass data  
<https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/>

#### Rights of the Data Subject

Right to access, rectification, right to object, to complaint, erasure and blockage.

You have the right to request information about whether and which personal data is processed by our company. You also have the right to demand that your personal data is rectified or amended. Under certain circumstances, you have the right to request that your personal data should be deleted. Under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand that the processing of your personal data should be restricted. You can withdraw your consent to the processing and use of your data completely or partially at any time with future application. You have the right to obtain your personal data in a common, structured and mechanically readable format.

If you have any questions, comments, complaints or requests in connection with our statement on data protection and the processing of your personal data, you can also contact our data protection officer in detail.

You also have the right to complain to the responsible supervisory authority if you believe that the processing of your personal data is in violation of the legislation.

#### Requirement of Obligation to Provide Data

Insofar as this is not expressly stated, when data are collected, the provision of data is neither required nor obligatory.

#### User Opt-Out

You can enact your concerned rights by using the following link. That includes, but is not limited to, the right to access, rectification, erasure and blockage of further collection (opt-out).

https://yieldkit.com/opt-out/

#### Date of Issue of this Data Privacy Statement

10.08.2018

We reserve the right to make amendments at any time to this data privacy statement for future effect.

This data privacy statement has been compiled with the assistance of ePrivacy GmbH.
